<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>performance on Andreas Gajdosik</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/tags/performance/</link><description>Recent content in performance on Andreas Gajdosik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 16:05:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gajdosik.org/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Raft of the Frogman</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/raft_of_the_frogman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/raft_of_the_frogman/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Veřejně prospěšné umělecké práce / Community Art Service</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/community_art_service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/community_art_service/</guid><description>In order to explore the meaning of art in times of pandemic and war, I decided to be radically useful. Wearing a work suit with the inscription &amp;ldquo;Community Art Service&amp;rdquo;, I cleaned up the city of Pardubice for a month. Freed from the pressure of assignments, demands and supervision of a traditional employer, as a free worker I let myself be openly guided and dérived by the situations, people and streets of an unknown city.</description></item><item><title>Black Fly Day</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/black_fly_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/black_fly_day/</guid><description>Using industrial waste from material bank provided by PLATO I have created two boxes for cultivation of meat flies in the exhibition space. Grown-up flies were later released by me in two big shopping malls in the Ostrava city. Black Fly Day (2020) is an object/intervention created for the exhibition Sand in the Gears in gallery PLATO Ostrava.</description></item><item><title>Power Play</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/power_play/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/power_play/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rtutík / Mercurie</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mercurie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mercurie/</guid><description>In 2019 the Regional Office in Pardubice approved emission exception for Chvaletice power plant. The exeption allowed the power plant to emit 300 kilograms of mercury over the normal emission limit. During the action days of czech Climate Camp 2019 I have realized a protest performance in the streets of Pardubice. Covered in thermofoil I have played huge droplet of mercury flowing through the city and spreading the word about beauties of mercury.</description></item><item><title>One Hour of Work</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/one_hour_of_work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/one_hour_of_work/</guid><description>One Hour of Work (2014) is series of 3 photographs. The photographs do not only refer working author or his graphical card on visual basis but also on capitalist level: earned money were used for printing of the actual pictures. Thus the more earning work, the bigger photography.</description></item></channel></rss>