<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>climate change on Andreas Gajdosik</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/tags/climate-change/</link><description>Recent content in climate change on Andreas Gajdosik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 16:05:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gajdosik.org/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Raft of the Frogman</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/raft_of_the_frogman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/raft_of_the_frogman/</guid><description>Performance as an interface between IT worker, frog in a pot, grotesque and ecological tragedy.
I created a floating monument of recycling out of waste plastic containers for motor oil as a solution for unlimited production. Dressed in normcore clothing, I then took to the water to celebrate the triumph of man over the impact of man with three victorious frog leaps. Then it got ugly.
Vacation on a warming lake turned into a nightmare for the unaware ICT worker, Mr Froggie (1-99).</description></item><item><title>Caravanitas</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/caravanitas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/caravanitas/</guid><description>Caravanitas (2023), a series of tourist postcards created for the city of Le Mans, combines the vanitas genre with the interiors and exteriors of contemporary cars through the technique of 3D rendering manipulated by artificial intelligence. It is a meditation on the impermanence not only of the individual but also of entire ecosystems in the context of the climate crisis and the city made famous by the 24 Hours of Le Mans car race.</description></item><item><title>Rtutík / Mercurie</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mercurie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mercurie/</guid><description>In 2019 the Regional Office in Pardubice approved emission exception for Chvaletice power plant. The exeption allowed the power plant to emit 300 kilograms of mercury over the normal emission limit. During the action days of czech Climate Camp 2019 I have realized a protest performance in the streets of Pardubice. Covered in thermofoil I have played huge droplet of mercury flowing through the city and spreading the word about beauties of mercury.</description></item></channel></rss>