<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software on Andreas Gajdosik</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in software on Andreas Gajdosik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:05:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gajdosik.org/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nejvyzkum.cz</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nejvyzkum/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nejvyzkum/</guid><description>link:https://nejvyzkum.cz[Nejvyzkum.cz]: nejlepší z možných výzkumů (in english: Bestresearch.cz: Best of All Possible Researches) is a subversive online psychological test created in collaboration with Barbora Šimková. Unlike normal psychological tests the Nejvyzkum.cz is not focused on testing its users - instead it uses crowdsourced prejudice of its users to test top 100 of Czech billionaires. The questions taken from Somatic Checklist 90 test and BigFive personality test are presented with random pairs of billionaires&amp;rsquo; faces to the visitors who then choose which one of the two most likely fits into the question.</description></item><item><title>Nomin</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nomin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nomin/</guid><description>Nomin (2017-2018) is project in progress on the edge of software, institutional critique and collective performance. Its main goal is to help artists from weakened social groups (students, pregnant artists, those who live outside big centers, easterners) with acceleration of their careers.
For this purpose I have created an open source GUI application for Linux, Mac and Windows called Nomin which provides its users the ability of sending fake emails from addresses of famous curators to the mailboxes of selected galleries or other institutions.</description></item><item><title>Rumours to MIDI</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/rumours_to_midi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/rumours_to_midi/</guid><description>Rumours to MIDI (2015) is a custom program written in Python. It scans Twitter for selected words and in real time it generates MIDI notes. Thus it can be used to produce strange rhytms or melodies from information all around the world.</description></item></channel></rss>