<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>netart on Andreas Gajdosik</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/tags/netart/</link><description>Recent content in netart on Andreas Gajdosik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:05:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gajdosik.org/tags/netart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nejvyzkum.cz</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nejvyzkum/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nejvyzkum/</guid><description>link:https://nejvyzkum.cz[Nejvyzkum.cz]: nejlepší z možných výzkumů (in english: Bestresearch.cz: Best of All Possible Researches) is a subversive online psychological test created in collaboration with Barbora Šimková. Unlike normal psychological tests the Nejvyzkum.cz is not focused on testing its users - instead it uses crowdsourced prejudice of its users to test top 100 of Czech billionaires. The questions taken from Somatic Checklist 90 test and BigFive personality test are presented with random pairs of billionaires&amp;rsquo; faces to the visitors who then choose which one of the two most likely fits into the question.</description></item><item><title>Unhuman Resources</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/unhuman_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/unhuman_resources/</guid><description>Unhuman Resources is online media intervention thematizing the power of Czech prime minister Andrej Babiš over news servers link:https://idnes.cz[idnes.cz] and link:https://lidovky.cz[lidovky.cz] which he both owns. It consists of two fake web pages link:https://l-dnes.cz[l-dnes.cz] and link:https://1idovky.cz[1idovky.cz] (later link:https://lidov.ky[lidov.ky]) which mocks their original versions by altering the text of every article. In these edits which appears on every mention of Babis&amp;rsquo;s name, his political party ANO, or just randomly at the ends of paragraphs, the (fictional) toxic relationship of owner and employee is slowly revealed.</description></item><item><title>NarodniLiga.cz</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/narodni_liga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/narodni_liga/</guid><description>Narodniliga.cz/NationalLeague.cz (2016) is a fake web of czech anti-islamic movement. It gathers data from Facebook groups which are focused against refugees and islam and makes daily, weekly and monthly rankings. Those who were commenting most are then winners of the league.
However what on on first sight looks like a classic right wing web page - colored with tricolora - later gives unpleasant image of czech anti-islamic movement. The page is full of real comments whose authors sends other people to gas, who wish them drowning in sea, full of vulgarisms etc.</description></item></channel></rss>