<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>intervention on Andreas Gajdosik</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/tags/intervention/</link><description>Recent content in intervention on Andreas Gajdosik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:05:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gajdosik.org/tags/intervention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caravanitas</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/caravanitas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/caravanitas/</guid><description>Caravanitas (2023), a series of tourist postcards created for the city of Le Mans, combines the vanitas genre with the interiors and exteriors of contemporary cars through the technique of 3D rendering manipulated by artificial intelligence. It is a meditation on the impermanence not only of the individual but also of entire ecosystems in the context of the climate crisis and the city made famous by the 24 Hours of Le Mans car race.</description></item><item><title>Tauto</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/tauto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/tauto/</guid><description>Tauto is artistic software for activists and anybody else which allows to spread comments on Twitter. It is a command line tool to automate interactions of bot accounts on Twitter via Twitter&amp;rsquo;s graphical user interface (website in browser). Tauto is thus capable of interactions which are not available through Twitter API or which could be blocked if used in high volumes via API. Exploring the space of evil media it is a sarcastic comment on bot farms, but also a useful piece of software.</description></item><item><title>Black Fly Day</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/black_fly_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/black_fly_day/</guid><description>Using industrial waste from material bank provided by PLATO I have created two boxes for cultivation of meat flies in the exhibition space. Grown-up flies were later released by me in two big shopping malls in the Ostrava city. Black Fly Day (2020) is an object/intervention created for the exhibition Sand in the Gears in gallery PLATO Ostrava.</description></item><item><title>Rtutík / Mercurie</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mercurie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mercurie/</guid><description>In 2019 the Regional Office in Pardubice approved emission exception for Chvaletice power plant. The exeption allowed the power plant to emit 300 kilograms of mercury over the normal emission limit. During the action days of czech Climate Camp 2019 I have realized a protest performance in the streets of Pardubice. Covered in thermofoil I have played huge droplet of mercury flowing through the city and spreading the word about beauties of mercury.</description></item><item><title>Unhuman Resources</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/unhuman_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/unhuman_resources/</guid><description>Unhuman Resources is online media intervention thematizing the power of Czech prime minister Andrej Babiš over news servers link:https://idnes.cz[idnes.cz] and link:https://lidovky.cz[lidovky.cz] which he both owns. It consists of two fake web pages link:https://l-dnes.cz[l-dnes.cz] and link:https://1idovky.cz[1idovky.cz] (later link:https://lidov.ky[lidov.ky]) which mocks their original versions by altering the text of every article. In these edits which appears on every mention of Babis&amp;rsquo;s name, his political party ANO, or just randomly at the ends of paragraphs, the (fictional) toxic relationship of owner and employee is slowly revealed.</description></item><item><title>Conclusions of Police Investigation</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/conclusions_of_police_investigation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/conclusions_of_police_investigation/</guid><description>Conclusions of Police Investigation is a site-specific video created for exhibition at gallery Umakart. In the video two persons are playing a board game Unusual Suspects. In this game one person is the witness to a crime. He knows who the culprit is but can only answer “Yes” or “No” to questions about the suspect. The second person is a detective trying to make sure the right person gets locked up from a line up of twelve hand drawn suspects.</description></item><item><title>Mailbox for Feedback</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mailbox_for_feedback/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mailbox_for_feedback/</guid><description>I have installed a mailbox on stairs near main classrooms of Faculty of Fine Arts in Brno. It asks employees, students and visitors to write down their ideas on what is and what is not working well on the faculty. Even though the mailbox was installed as a guerilla act the text on it used official language and looked like it was realized by the faculty. Later I have sent to the Dean a letter containg keys for the mailbox and also stating: ‘I thought it could be useful, so I did it.</description></item><item><title>Nomin</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nomin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/nomin/</guid><description>Nomin (2017-2018) is project in progress on the edge of software, institutional critique and collective performance. Its main goal is to help artists from weakened social groups (students, pregnant artists, those who live outside big centers, easterners) with acceleration of their careers.
For this purpose I have created an open source GUI application for Linux, Mac and Windows called Nomin which provides its users the ability of sending fake emails from addresses of famous curators to the mailboxes of selected galleries or other institutions.</description></item><item><title>Mail from mr. Ondracka</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mail_from_ondracka/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/mail_from_ondracka/</guid><description>Using custom bash script and telnet I have sent fake mail to vast majority of students at Faculty of Fine Arts. The mail looked like if it was from Vice-Dean for student affairs Pavel Ondracka: it has his email address in the header, used his style of language and welcomed all students in new building of FFA.
However it also announced several changes in the organozation of the study and faculty.</description></item><item><title>Sauna / What Dean Promised I am Doing</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/sauna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/sauna/</guid><description>As part of pre-election promises for both terms the current dean of Faculty of Fine Arts promised a school sauna for students and employees of faculty. However this populist promise was never realized. To react I took his promise seriously and tried my best… Sauna was operating from January 2017 to March 2017, freely open to all students, employees and visitors of faculty.</description></item><item><title>NarodniLiga.cz</title><link>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/narodni_liga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 16:05:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gajdosik.org/artworks/narodni_liga/</guid><description>Narodniliga.cz/NationalLeague.cz (2016) is a fake web of czech anti-islamic movement. It gathers data from Facebook groups which are focused against refugees and islam and makes daily, weekly and monthly rankings. Those who were commenting most are then winners of the league.
However what on on first sight looks like a classic right wing web page - colored with tricolora - later gives unpleasant image of czech anti-islamic movement. The page is full of real comments whose authors sends other people to gas, who wish them drowning in sea, full of vulgarisms etc.</description></item></channel></rss>